It's been a while since I came to such a fancy restaurant.
好久没来这么豪华的餐厅了
It's so exciting.
感觉好兴奋呢
Mai. You can drink as much as you want.
小舞 你今天可以尽情喝了
Tell us everything. We're all ears.
我们会听你诉苦的
What?
什么？
Like why you were dumped by your boyfriend.
比如说你被男朋友甩了的事啊
I was not dumped. We just broke up, that's all.
我没有被甩 我们是和平分手的
Tell us everything, including all of that.
我们会慢慢听你说
You have permission to drink until you lose your memory and pass out.
你今天要喝到断片暴走都没问题
Aki. Yuri.
亚纪 友梨
It's so nice to have girlfriends.
有闺蜜的感觉真好啊
Same here.
瞧你这话说的
Let's drink tonight.
好 那今天不醉不归
YONOSUKE
（醉之助居酒屋）
Let's see…
看看啊
Fried squid, beef stew…
鱿鱼圈 炖牛筋
The fried chicken sounds good too.
超大份炸鸡看起来也好好吃啊
We just got paid, so let's go all out.
我们刚发了工资 今天就尽情吃吧
Yes.
对
I'm sure my wife will understand.
我老婆一定会理解我的
Let's order all of it.
干脆全部点了吧
Sure.
好的
Mai, is it just you and your boss at your workplace?
小舞 你工作的部门 至今还是只有你和上司两个人吗？
Yup, usually.
是啊 一样
How can you stand that?
你怎么忍受得了啊？
I don't think I could do that. It would be so uncomfortable.
换做是我 肯定干不下去 太别扭了
He's all right.
他还好啊
He's easy-going so I don't care.
他很随和 所以我也没关系
You sound like someone who's been married for a long time.
听起来像老夫老妻似的
What do you mean?
你说什么呢？
I have a good idea.
对了
Can't he be your next boyfriend?
他可以当你下一任男友的人选啊
No way! Stop joking. He's kind of old.
拜托 别开玩笑了 他可是大叔啊
How old is he?
他几岁啊？
He's about 15 years older than me.
他比我大15岁左右吧
That's not a problem.
那完全没问题啊
That's even better.
甚至更好呢
Are you serious?
不是吧？
-Cheers.
-辛苦了
It's Mr. Karashima.
是辛岛部长打来的
Sorry…
辛苦了
Cheers!
-干杯
MR. SOMA
（相马来电）
Sorry. Start without me.
抱歉 你们先喝
This is Hanasaki.
喂？我是花琦
Inspection.
稽核
Next Monday?
下周一吗？
No. It's an emergency inspection. We have to go now.
不 是紧急稽核 现在马上
What?
什么？
Right now?
现在马上吗？
Yeah.
是的
But…
可是…
This is delicious.
-好好喝
I really don't feel like going either.
我也很不想去啊
Sorry, but I'll leave it to you.
不好意思 拜托你们了
Okay…
是
Cash was lost at the Roppongi Branch.
六本木分行有现金不见了
Cash?
现金？
Cash was lost? How much?
不见了多少现金？
Three million yen.
三百万日元
Three million yen?
三百万日元？
TOKYO DAIICHI BANK
（东京第一银行）
TOKYO DAIICHI BANK ROPPONGI BRANCH
（东京第一银行 六本木分行）
I am Kanda, the Sales Section Chief.
我是营业课长神田
Branch Manager is on his way back from a business trip.
分行经理刚结束出差 正在赶回来的途中
I will be in charge until he is back.
在那之前 由我负责
-Thank you.
-请多关照
The Sales Department are all here.
营业部的人都在这里了
TELLER, KYOKO YOSHIKAWA
（出纳员 吉川恭子）
I can't believe this is happening while the Branch Manager is away.
真不敢相信经理不在的时候 竟然发生了这么大的事
Can you tell us the sequence of events after you found out the cash was lost?
请你告诉我们发现现金遗失的始末
Yes.
好
It was around 3:30 p.m. when we noticed that the cash was unbalanced.
今天下午3点半左右 我们发现账目对不上
What?
什么？
We are three million yen short?
少了三百万？
We've calculated many times, but it doesn't balance.
我们算很多次了 就是对不上
Whose window?
是哪个柜台？
Ms. Masuno.
是枡野的柜台
I am very sorry.
非常抱歉
Check the slips and automatic cashier for any errors.
可能是票据 或电子出纳记录的输入错误
Check everything you can think of.
把能想到的问题都查一遍
Yes, sir.
-是
Check the drawers and garbage.
抽屉和垃圾桶也要检查
Check everything on this floor.
把这一层楼都搜一遍
Yes, sir.
-是
Check the garbage room!
-找个人去垃圾房找找
Um…
还有…
Let's check the security camera.
看一下监视器
We've checked everything.
我们都找过了
But we can't find it.
都没有找到
I see.
这样啊
Um…
那个…
It's hard to say this, but…
虽然有些难以启齿
We were busy today because it is the pay-day before the weekend.
但今天因为是周末前发工资的日子 比往常要忙得多
So the cash management was not as thorough as it should've been.
所以对于现金的管理并没有彻底做好
What do you mean?
什么意思？
Um…
那个…
The tellers shared passwords for the teller machine
我们几个出纳员共用了出纳机密码
to withdraw cash.
方便取出现金
ENTER THE PASSWORD
（请输入密码）
We wanted to save time.
这也是为了提高效率
Thank you.
谢谢
-I'll put it here. -Thank you.
-我就放这里了 -谢谢
I see.
原来如此
That made it harder to track the money flow.
这样一来钱的去向就难以追踪了
Yes. I am sorry.
是的 真是抱歉
I didn't take part in that.
这不关我的事哦
That's why I'm always telling you guys not to break the rules.
我不是一直跟你们说 不要做这种违反规定的事吗？
I am very sorry.
-对不起
Could it be an over-payment?
会不会是多给客户钱了？
We called all the customers who received over one million yen.
我们联系了 取出现金一百万日元以上的客户
But they said they didn't receive extra,
他们全都说没有多拿
and as far as I could see on the security camera,
而且我检查了监视器
I didn't see Ms. Masuno giving the customers an extra bundle of cash.
并没有发现枡野 有多给一百万日元现金
Did you check carefully?
课长 你仔细看了吗？
Yes, of course.
当然了
Um…
那个…
It's probably not an over-payment.
大概不是多交了款项吧？
Over-payments are errors by the teller.
如果是多给钱 的确是出纳员的失误
It's not impossible to mistakenly give one extra bundle of
如果是多给一捆一百万日元现金
a million yen.
那也不是不可能
But I think it's impossible to mistakenly hand someone three extra bundles.
但是多给三捆一百万这种事 一般来说是不可能的吧？
Then…
那么
Do you want to say that someone hid the cash on purpose?
你是说有人故意把现金藏起来了吗？
That's not what I meant.
我不是这个意思
Could it be…
难道…
embezzlement?
是盗用？
We have to think about that possibility too.
这种可能性也必须考虑
Mr. Soma.
相马先生
What should we do?
那我们该怎么办？
We may need to check your personal belongings.
我们需要检查一下个人物品
-Check our personal belongings? -You mean…
-检查个人物品？ -检查个人物品吗？
You mean us too?
我们也得查吗？
Yes.
是的
Everyone, I understand your cause for complaint.
各位 我知道你们有所不满
However, if we cannot find the three million yen
但如果我们找不回那三百万
everyone on this sales floor will be called
你们营业楼层的全体职员
to the Inquiry Commission at headquarters.
都会被本部的调查委员会问话
Let's do it.
开始吧！
We will check your personal belongings.
各位 开始个人物品检查
First this floor, then the locker room.
首先是这个楼层 然後是储物柜
Please place everything in your bag onto your desk.
请把包包里的东西全部放到桌面上
Let's start.
来 快点
If looks could kill…
他们的眼神太恐怖了
Playing the villain at a time like this, is also the role of a Branch Inspector.
在这种时候当坏人 也是我们分行稽核班的工作之一
Everything is okay. Thank you very much.
没有问题 谢谢合作
We're done with the male employees.
男性职员的检查结束了
Thank you very much.
谢谢
Next…
那接下来
Ms. Ryoko Izawa.
伊泽良子小姐
Why do I have to do this?
为什么连我都要遭受这种待遇？
I am sorry. Excuse me.
对不起 失礼了
I don't see any problem.
看起来没有什么问题
Of course not.
当然了
Thank you very much.
谢谢合作
Ms. Kyoko Yoshikawa.
吉川恭子小姐
Yes.
是
This is mine.
拜托你了
Excuse me.
失礼了
Nothing.
没有问题
Thank you very much.
谢谢合作
-Ms. Rie Masuno. -Yes.
-枡野理江小姐 -是
Ms. Hanasaki.
花琦小姐
Be extra thorough.
你可得格外仔细检查她
Excuse me.
失礼了
Do you mind if I open this?
请问这个可以打开看看吗？
-But… -Is there anything you can't show her?
-但是… -有什么不能让人看的东西吗？
May I?
可以吗？
-Yes. -Excuse me.
-可以 -失礼了
You smoke?
你抽烟吗？
-Sorry. -So misleading!
-对不起 -干嘛混淆视听啊？
Okay.
好了
This is fine. Thank you very much.
没有问题 谢谢合作
TOKYO DAIICHI BANK HEADQUARTERS
（东京第一银行本部）
Cash is missing?
丢失现金？
Yes. Branch Inspection is at the Roppongi Branch right now.
是的 分行稽核班现在就在六本木分行
But it's not been found yet.
但是还没有找到
Three million yen.
三百万吗？
-Who's the Branch Manager at Roppongi? -Kubodera.
-六本木分行的经理是谁？ -是久保寺
EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR TSUYOSHI SHINDO
（常务执行董事 真藤毅）
Kubodera?
久保寺？
SECRETARIAL OFFICE ASSISTANT GM: NAOKI KODAMA
（秘书室次长 儿玉直树）
He is in Senior Executive Director Doujima's faction.
是堂岛专务那一派的
I see.
原来如此
I feel sorry for Senior Executive Director Doujima.
堂岛专务也真是可怜啊
It's a troublesome issue right after he landed this new post.
刚一上任就出了这种麻烦事
I agree.
是啊
You won't be able to do as you like
接下来可不会再让你
from now on.
任意妄为了
The check is complete.
检查到此结束
Thank you very much for your cooperation.
非常感谢大家的配合
The culprit should step forward,
犯人再不快点出来自首的话
or it will make things awkward at this branch.
我们分行的气氛都要变糟了
This is not good.
真令人头疼啊
If we find the cash, it means there is a criminal in this branch.
如果找到了现金 就表示犯人是内贼
But not finding three million is also a problem.
如果找不到 也很伤脑筋
I understand.
我了解你的感受
-Mr. Kanda. -Branch Manager.
-神田课长 -经理
I'm Soma from Branch Inspection.
我是分行稽核班的相马
I am Kubodera, the Branch Manager.
我是分行经理久保寺
BRANCH MANAGER TOSHIYA KUBODERA
（分行经理 久保寺敏也）
Did you find it?
你们找到了吗？
Not yet.
还没有
I see.
是吗？
This is a serious problem.
这下可不妙了啊
Um…
那个…
It is not fair to treat Ms. Masuno as a criminal.
你这样一口咬定枡野小姐就是犯人 不太好吧？
This is her responsibility, that's a fact.
但是责任确实在她啊
If we can't find it,
如果还是找不到的话
we will continue to be suspects, even though we are innocent.
连我们这些无辜职员都要一直被怀疑
All because of Ms. Masuno.
都是枡野的错
You'll never understand how humiliating that is,
我们现在有多么屈辱
because you are from headquarters.
你们本部的人怎么会清楚？
Ms. Masuno is also feeling the humiliation
但是莫名遭到怀疑的枡野小姐 受到的屈辱
of being suspected of embezzlement.
也和大家一样啊
I know how much responsibility a teller holds for their own window.
我非常明白出纳员在自己的柜台 要承担多大的责任
I used to be a teller.
因为我曾经也是出纳员
We tried hard, but we still couldn't find the cash.
就算再怎么搜查 还是找不到现金
It can't be helped.
这就没办法了
Let's call it a day.
今天就解散吧
Thank you for your cooperation.
辛苦各位了
Thank you.
-辛苦了
Thank you for your hard work.
也辛苦你们了
We will come again.
我们会再拜访的
-Thank you. -Yes.
-拜托你们了 -好的
Good night.
辛苦了
Thank you for everything.
真是太感激你们了
No…
不客气
At this rate, everyone will be suspicious of each other,
只是这样下去 员工之间会互相猜疑
and it will end up making the atmosphere even worse.
最后气氛会变得更糟糕
Yes.
是啊
Anyways, we must find the cash.
总之 我们得赶紧查清现金的下落
It's causing me stress.
真是让人紧张啊
Are you okay?
没事吧？
Yes.
没事
Ms. Hanasaki.
花琦小姐
Thank you for standing up for me earlier.
多谢你刚刚为我说话
I may have overstepped my boundaries.
可是我好像说了些不该说的话呢
I was in a panic when it was busy with lots of customers.
那时客人很多 我整个人都慌了
If someone were to ask me if I processed the cash properly,
所以被问到当时有没有好好处理现金
or if I didn't make any errors, I couldn't answer with confidence.
或是有没有犯错的时候 我也不敢确定地说没有
But I swear that I did not steal it.
但我发誓 我绝对没偷那笔钱
Yes.
我知道了
Excuse me.
那我先走了
Good night.
辛苦了
RESTAURANT HANASAKI
（花琦居酒屋）
I wonder if we can find the three million yen.
三百万啊 能找得到吗？
I don't know.
不知道
Do you think someone embezzled it?
你也觉得是被人盗用了吗？
I don't want to think that, but it's hard to deny that possibility.
我也不想这么想 但这可能性是最高的
With accidents involving cash, even if we were to retrieve it back
像这样的金钱事故 就算之后把钱找回来了
it doesn't mean that we'll also find the culprit behind it.
也不见得能找出真正的犯人
The principal of the bank is "cash leaves no trail."
因为银行的原则就是现金不留痕迹
We must catch them in the act.
我们只能在犯案现场逮人了
Which means we may not find out the truth.
也就是说 可能无法查明真相了
You both look so gloomy.
你们两个怎么一脸郁闷？
We have many problems.
很多烦心事啊
MAI'S DAD KOZO HANASAKI
（小舞父亲 花琦幸三）
What happened?
怎么了？
Listen to this. In the Roppongi Branch--
就是那个六本木分行啊…
We can't say. It's confidential.
不能说 要保密啦
-Sorry. -I see.
-不好意思 -这样啊
Ah… chocolate.
巧克力
Give me one. I've been wanting sweets.
给我一个 我一直好想吃甜的
Can I have one too?
我也能要一个吗？
Sorry, but they're all gone.
抱歉 已经没巧克力了
Is that dried bonito?
里面放的是鲣鱼干吗？
Yes. This is the perfect size for this.
对啊 大小正好
How misleading.
干嘛混淆视听啊？
What's written on the box isn't always what's inside.
谁规定盒子必须得表里一致啊？
Oh, I forgot.
对了
I wanted to eat something sweet.
我好想吃甜食啊
I will go to a convenience store on my way back home.
那我回去的时候 顺便去一趟便利商店吧
-Mr. Soma. -Yeah?
-相马 -怎么了？
What will you do about the Roppongi Branch?
六本木分行的事情怎么办啊？
We've done everything we can. What else can we do?
能做的事我们都做了 还能怎么办？
I feel sorry for Ms. Masuno with the way things are.
这样下去 枡野小姐就太可怜了
I know.
就是说啊
I wonder when the cash left that branch.
那笔钱到底是什么时候不见的呢？
There is a moment when three million yen became lost, right?
那三百万应该是 从某个瞬间开始不见的吧？
Yes, that moment surely exists.
对 应该会有一个时间点
I want to check the footage from the security camera.
我想看看监视器
No, Mr. Kanda said that he checked it already.
但是神田课长说他已经看过了
If I look at it from the point of view of a former teller,
可是我用前任出纳员的角度来看的话
I may be able to find something that he overlooked.
说不定会发现什么他没看到的
TOKYO DAIICHI BANK ROPPONGI BRANCH
（东京第一银行六本木分行）
These are the transaction slips from Friday.
这些就是周五的交易单据
Thank you very much.
谢谢
You're going to check them all?
你们真的要全部重新检查一遍吗？
Yes. I want to check them in chronological order.
对 我们想按照时间顺序再确认一遍
This is a lot.
有这么多啊
I will help you.
不如 我也来帮忙吧
Thank you very much.
那就谢谢你了
The way Ms. Yoshikawa works is very careful, fast, and precise.
吉川小姐工作的时候 真是仔细 快速又精准啊
I feel like this is double speed.
简直像在看加速影片一样
Yes. I feel comfortable entrusting her with everything.
是啊 无论什么工作 只要交给吉川 我就放心了
Is there anything?
怎么了吗？
There's a lady who came back after finishing her transaction
有个刚办完手续的女士好像又出现了
and received something from Ms. Yoshikawa.
还从吉川小姐那里拿了什么
Look at this.
就是这个
It can't be…
莫非…
No. That's a pack of tissues.
不对 只是纸巾而已吧？
-You are right. -Hey!
-真的耶 -搞什么啊？
Sorry.
不好意思
I remember her.
我记得她
She said she wanted a clock we distribute as a novelty item.
她一直缠着我们要钟表赠品呢
The table clock?
就是那个钟表吗？
Yes. Let me see.
是啊 我找找
This is it.
就是这个
She saw the other customers getting it.
她看到别的顾客收到过
Yes, there are customers like that. Here it is.
常常遇到这样的顾客呢 就是这个
Yeah, this is not the kind of novelty item we'd give to just anyone.
毕竟这不是随随便便 就能送出去的赠品啊
This is for the customers
是的 这个只会送给
who open a fixed deposit account of over one million yen.
定期存款里 储存超过一百万日元的客户
She came to the window just to make a new passbook.
这位女士只是来转账而已
Usually we'd end up giving it to someone who's this persistent.
但是对于一直纠缠的顾客 我们通常都会给她了事
I'm surprised she left with just some tissues.
可是她竟然只拿了几包纸巾就走了
I guess Ms. Yoshikawa really plays by the book.
吉川小姐真是个办事认真的人啊
More than that, she's very meticulous.
不止认真 她做事简直是严谨
I can imagine that.
看得出来
BRANDAGE KOUICHI BABA
（马场浩一）
Huh?
嗯？
What now?
又怎么了？
I just found something strange…
我觉得有点奇怪
Ms. Yoshikawa gave the clock to this customer.
吉川小姐把钟表送给这位顾客了
-A clock? -Yes.
-钟表？ -是
This customer only came in to withdraw 150,000 yen.
这个顾客只不过是提款15万元而已
What?
什么？
Even though she refused to give it to the other customer.
刚刚都那样拒绝那位女士了
This isn't like Ms. Yoshikawa. I wonder what happened.
这不像吉川的作风啊 怎么回事？
Did she give it to him because he's her friend?
会不会是熟人 所以就给他了？
Well, I don't think Ms. Yoshikawa would do something like that.
我觉得吉川应该不会做这种事情
How misleading.
干嘛混淆视听啊？
What's written on the box isn't always what's inside.
谁规定盒子必须得表里一致啊？
There might have been something else inside.
说不定里面装着别的东西
Inside?
里面？
Let me check.
我看看
Look at this box.
你们看这个盒子
Don't you think it would fit three bundles of one million yen?
不是放得进 三捆一百万元的钞票吗？
You're right. This is the right size.
是啊 大小正合适呢
Wait a minute.
请等一下
You're saying that Ms. Yoshikawa put three million yen in here
你们是说吉川把三百万装在这里面
and gave it to him?
然后交给别人了吗？
There's no way she'd conspire with a customer to do that.
她不可能和顾客勾结做这种事的
But if it's placed in here and handed off,
但是把钱放进这个盒子里
cash can be taken out without anyone realizing it.
就能神不知鬼不觉地把钱带出去了
Right.
确实
But…
怎么会？
Customers are called, in the order of the ticket number.
顾客们是按号码牌来办理业务的
So there was no guarantee that this customer would get Ms. Yoshikawa's window.
他也不一定会正好来到吉川的柜台吧
Yes, she could.
不 可以做到的
Ms. Yoshikawa is an experienced teller.
像吉川小姐这样专业的出纳员
She's able to adjust the transaction time so that
可以透过调整自己的业务处理时间
she gets a certain customer at her window.
让某位指定号码的客户 来到自己的柜台
But even if she's able to do that,
就算她做得到
I don't think she would do such a thing.
也不可能做这种事吧？
Who is that customer?
这位顾客是谁？
It's Mr. Kouichi Baba of Brandage Ltd.
是布兰德吉有限公司的马场浩一
Who is he?
他是做什么的？
He runs an import goods store in Azabu.
他在麻布经营一家进口杂货店
I don't know much about him.
具体的我不清楚
He got a loan from us.
我们跟他有融资的往来
Business with Brandage started three years ago.
与布兰德吉的交易是从三年前开始的
The loan balance is ten million yen?
贷款余额是一千万？
Yes. He's applying for an additional loan right now.
是 对方还提出了追加贷款
The decision will be made tomorrow, but we will most likely turn it down.
明天将会作出结论 但我想应该会被拒绝吧
They're not doing well?
他们业绩不好吗？
Lately, they're in the red.
他们最近一直是赤字
In the red…
赤字…
Excuse me.
不好意思
President Baba? Okay. I'll be there in a minute.
马场社长？好 我马上过去
Excuse me. Mr. Baba is here.
不好意思 马场社长来了 我先走了
Thank you.
谢谢
Thank you for waiting.
让你久等了
PRESIDENT OF BRANDAGE LTD. KOUICHI BABA
（布兰德吉社长 马场浩一）
I wanted to ask about the additional loan.
请问追加贷款的事情怎么样了？
I am sorry, but we're still in the process of discussing it.
对不起 银行还在商议
I really need this.
我真的很需要这笔钱
I need your support, Mr. Kiyama.
拜托你想想办法 木山先生
Yes.
好的
I will be waiting for a favorable answer.
总之 我等你的好消息
Mr. Kanda.
神田课长
I will borrow this.
这个借我一下
-What? -Hey.
-什么？ -喂
-Mr. Baba. -Yes?
-马场社长 -是
Please take this with you.
请你收下这个
What?
什么？
This is our popular novelty item.
这是我们很受欢迎的赠品哦
It is a gift to you for using our bank.
感谢你对我们的关照
Do you already have one, by any chance?
还是说你已经拿过了？
No, I don't.
没有
Good. Then please take it with you.
那好 那请你收下吧
Thank you.
谢谢
Thank you for using our bank.
今后还请你多多关照
You almost gave me a heart attack.
我差点要心脏病发了
But now we know that Mr. Baba has never seen that clock before.
但如此一来 我们就知道 马场社长没有见过那个钟表
That's right.
也是
The box Ms. Yoshikawa gave to President Baba
吉川小姐给马场先生的盒子里
did not have a clock in it after all.
果然不是装着钟表
Ms. Yoshikawa is a very serious and hardworking teller,
吉川是个非常认真努力的出纳员
who is trusted by the customers.
深受客户信赖
I don't want to believe it.
真是难以置信
CLOSED
（休息中）
Hearing Ms. Yoshikawa's personality
听别人说吉川小姐的人品
makes me feel that our assumptions are wrong.
我都怀疑我们的推论好像错了
Serious-minded people can get out of control,
认真的人一旦偏离了正轨就会失控
once they stray from the right path.
这也是有可能的
Mr. Soma.
相马
Let's follow her.
我们跟踪她吧
We don't have to do that.
没这个必要吧？
We may be able to find something.
也许可以发现什么啊
Taxi.
有车
Hey!
喂
Excuse me!
不好意思
Hanasaki.
花琦
Hurry up, Mr. Soma!
相马 快点
Damn it.
真是的
Please follow the taxi in front of us.
麻烦跟上前面的计程车
We are not detectives.
我们又不是警察
Can we get this reimbursed?
这个发票能报销吗？
Hurry up.
快点
It's 1,230 yen.
1230日元啊
Don't push me, you idiot.
别推我啦 笨蛋
Isn't that Brandage?
这不是布兰德吉吗？
-Hey. Let's go. -Yes.
-走吧 -好
-Which way? -That way.
-走哪边？ -这边
They look very close.
看起来很亲密啊
I don't think they just met yesterday.
不像是昨天才认识的朋友呢
BRANCH MANAGER'S OFFICE
（分行经理办公室）
What? Ms. Yoshikawa and President Baba?
什么？吉川和马场社长？
Yes. I think they are in a relationship.
对 他们应该是在交往
This is the transaction record of Ms. Yoshikawa's account.
这是吉川小姐账户的进出款记录
Her money has been
她的钱
used to pay rent and energy bills, sending money home, fixed deposit,
都是用来交房租 煤电费、家用、定期存款
and life insurance.
还有人寿保险
A set amount was being used from her account every month.
每个月都是固定的金额流向
But a year ago,
但大概一年前
her withdrawals increased, and her balance decreased.
她的提款开始增加 余额慢慢减少
She cancelled her fixed deposit too.
还解除了未到期的定期存款
We ran a credit check on her
我们调查了她的个人信用
and found that she is over ten million yen in debt.
发现她身负将近一千万的借款
Most likely, she's giving all the money to President Baba.
恐怕是全都给了马场社长吧？
I didn't know Ms. Yoshikawa was in such trouble.
我都不知道吉川竟然做出这种事
She gave three million yen by hiding it in a novelty gift box.
她把三百万放在钟表盒子里 给了对方啊
TOKYO DAIICHI BANK
（东京第一银行）
We can't do anything without evidence.
可是没有证据的话 我们什么也做不了啊
She won't admit it even if we ask her.
就算问她 也不会承认吧？
Right.
没错
Excuse me.
打扰了
What's up, Kiyama?
怎么了 木山？
I just met President Baba of Brandage.
我刚刚见了布兰德吉的马场社长
I told him the request for an additional loan was declined.
告诉他追加贷款的请求被驳回了
He seems to be in a dire situation.
他看起来好像走投无路了
-Really? -Yes.
-是吗？ -是的
He said his request for Hakusei Bank was turned down too.
他说他向白水银行的申请也被拒绝了
He may not make it through this month.
可能熬不过这个月
When is the settlement?
布兰德吉的结算日是哪天？
End of the month.
月底
He may not have enough funds by then.
这样他也没办法还贷款吧？
That's highly possible.
非常有可能
What did Mr. Baba say?
马场社长怎么说？
He was very upset.
他很激动
Tokyo Daiichi Bank is abandoning me?
东京第一银行是准备 对我见死不救吗？
I see.
这样啊
I wanted to report to you first. Excuse me.
情况就是这样 我先出去了
Thank you.
谢谢
Branch Manager Kubodera.
久保寺经理
They may try the same thing again.
他们两个可能会故技重施
What?
什么？
Even though they succeeded once, I highly doubt
但就算他们成功过一次
they'll risk another attempt in such a short span of time.
短时间内不太可能又铤而走险吧？
But his company will go bankrupt if they don't do anything.
这样下去他的公司就会破产
We can't rule it out.
这是有可能的
I see.
说的也是
Last time, Ms. Yoshikawa embezzled money on the busiest day when
吉川小姐上一次 选了出纳员无暇多顾的繁忙日
the tellers were frantic.
盗用公款
If she is to try again, she will choose the busiest day.
如果再做一次的话 她应该还是会选择繁忙日吧？
Which would be the 31st.
那就是31号
If he gets money on the 31st, Brandage will not go bankrupt.
如果31号拿到钱 布兰德吉就能免于破产
If we catch the moment,
如果能当场逮到的话
we'll have evidence.
就可以成为证据了
Cash leaves no trail.
现金不留痕迹
We must catch that moment.
我们一定要抓住那个瞬间
Mai. I'm going to take a bath.
小舞 我先洗澡了
Go ahead.
去吧
What's wrong? You look serious.
怎么了？一脸严谨的
I have a question.
我问你哦
Were you able to do anything for Mom?
你为了妈妈 什么都能做吗？
Why this all of a sudden?
怎么突然这么问？
Just curious.
好奇啊
Well… I had regrets when she died
你妈妈去世的时候 我很后悔
because I thought I could've done more.
我觉得我做的事还不够多
I felt that I should've done more.
如果能多为她多做点什么就好了
Even if that was against the law?
就算是犯罪也做吗？
That sounds extreme.
那么极端的例子啊？
But it's possible if there's something you really want to protect.
不过 为了真心想守护的人 这也是有可能的
Whether you carry that out or not is another story.
只是会不会真的行动 就另当别论了
I see.
这样啊
I'll go now.
我先去洗了
You look so glum.
你这什么表情啊？
I bet you're thinking, "I don't want Ms. Yoshikawa to commit another crime."
你是希望吉川不会再罪加一等吧？
But she has already committed a crime,
但她已经犯罪了
by doing something a banker should never do.
她做了银行职员最不该做的事
She needs to be charged for that crime. It's for her own good.
她必须为此受罚 这是为了她好
It has to be today.
就看今天了
Yes.
知道了
Today is Friday, the 31st.
今天是31号周五
It is expected to be very busy.
因为预想到会相当忙碌
So I requested help from headquarters.
我们就从本部请来了支援
I am Hanasaki. I will do my best today.
我是花琦 今天一天请多多关照
Thank you.
-请多多关照
Please do your best today.
就是这样 今天拜托你们了
Yes.
-是
Ms. Hanasaki. I'm counting on you.
花琦小姐 拜托了
What happened to the three million?
那三百万怎么样了？
It was processed as a temporary advance for now.
目前先以预支款项处理了
I see. Either way, don't slow us down.
这样啊 总之 不要扯我们后腿哦
Yes. I will do my best.
是 请多多关照
-I will do my best. -Thank you.
-请多多关照
Ms. Yoshikawa, let's do our best.
吉川小姐 请多多关照
Thank you.
请多多关照
Now, let's see.
来看看吧
I wonder if he'll come.
他会来吗？
Good morning.
-欢迎光临 -早安
Thank you for waiting.
久等了
-Thank you very much. -Yes.
-谢谢
Customer with ticket number 115…
请115号顾客到柜台
-Here it is. -Okay.
-拜托了 -好
He came.
来了
CARD SLOT
（号码牌）
Thank you very much.
谢谢
Ms. Yoshikawa is an experienced teller.
像吉川小姐这样专业的出纳员
She's able to adjust the transaction time so that
可以透过调整自己的业务处理时间
she gets a certain customer at her window.
让某位指定号码的客户 来到自己的柜台
A withdrawal?
是要提款吗？
Thank you very much.
谢谢
Ms. Saga.
佐田女士
Here is 500,000 yen. Please confirm.
这是五十万日元 请你确认
Thank you very much.
谢谢
Customer with ticket number 384…
请385号顾客到柜台
Customer with ticket number 385, please come to window four.
请385号顾客到四号柜台
Good afternoon.
欢迎光临
Hello.
麻烦你了
A withdrawal?
是要提款吧？
Please wait a moment.
请稍等
Okay.
麻烦你了
Brandage Ltd.
布兰德吉有限公司
Here is 500,000 yen. Please confirm.
这是五十万日元 请你确认
Thank you.
谢谢
TOKYO DAIICHI BANK
（东京第一银行）
This is a gift from our bank.
请收下这个增品吧
Thank you.
谢谢
What is it?
干什么？
Mr. Baba. I think we gave you this clock the other day,
马场先生 我们之前已经给过你这款钟表了
so we'd like to offer you a different one today.
今天想给你另一款
What?
什么？
I'm sorry, but can you give that back to us?
抱歉 请问这个可以还给我们吗？
Excuse me.
劳烦你
Would you please come with me to the other room?
跟我到里面坐一坐吧
Excuse me, but I will step away from my window.
不好意思 我离开一下
Ms. Yoshikawa. You…
吉川 你…
The police will arrive soon.
警察马上就来了
President Baba, would you please tell us everything before the police arrive?
马场社长 在那之前 能请你坦白一切吗？
I will apologize in advance,
虽有冒犯的地方
but we investigated everything about you.
但有关你的事 我们都调查清楚了
You were…
你把钱
giving all of your money to Mr. Baba, right?
全都给了马场社长吧？
Why did you have to go that far?
为什么要做到这个地步呢？
How could you steal money from the bank?
你怎么可以盗用银行的钱？
You couldn't refuse?
是你无法拒绝他吗？
It was my decision.
这是我自己的决定
He didn't ask me to do this.
不是他的要求
I don't understand why you had to go this far.
我不明白你为什么要做到这地步
-Because-- -I'm marrying him.
-因为… -我要跟他结婚
When
跟他相遇
I met him, I felt that being on my own until then
让我第一次感觉到
was all worth it.
我一个人努力到现在都是值得的
Please check your passbook.
请你确认一下
Thank you.
谢谢
He made…
是他
my boring
让我那无聊
and dull life, bright and colorful.
又沉闷的日常生活变得多姿多彩
Let's go.
走吧
Yes.
好
SIX MONTHS BEHIND REPAYMENT SCHEDULE
（还款已拖欠六个月）
So…
所以
I wanted to do
为了他
all that I can for him.
我可以做任何事
Even if that was something I should never do as a banker
包括那些身为银行职员或出纳员
and a teller.
绝不能做的事
This is for you from our bank.
请收下这个赠品
Thank you.
谢谢
I knew it was something I should never do.
我知道我不应该那样做
But right now,
但现在
I'm feeling somewhat relieved.
我内心感觉松了一口气
I can finally end this.
这下子终于结束了
I knew this would happen someday,
我知道这一天一定会到来
but I couldn't end it on my own.
但我就是停不下来
I am sorry.
对不起
He is not bad at all.
他没有做错任何事
I planned everything and put it into action
这件事都是我一个人策划的
all on my own.
一个人实行的
Hanasaki.
花琦
Yes?
什么事？
I had President Baba investigated.
我调查了马场社长
INVESTIGATION REPORT
（调查报告书）
Ms. Yoshikawa was deceived.
吉川小姐…她被骗了
Like I said, I don't know anything.
我都说了 我什么都不知道
Why do I have to go to the police station?
为什么我非得去警局不可？
You're suspected as an accomplice of embezzlement.
你涉嫌合谋盗用公款
She did it all by herself.
都是她做的
I didn't know about the cash.
我完全不知道那里面装着钱
But you received three million yen on the 24th.
但24日那天 你不也拿了三百万吗？
I have no idea what you are talking about.
我根本不知道你说什么
You're despicable!
你这混蛋！
What are you doing?
你干什么啊？
You hit customers at this bank?
你们怎么能对客户动手？
Hanasaki, calm down!
花琦小姐 你冷静点
What Ms. Yoshikawa did was a crime.
吉川小姐做的事是犯罪
But she had been living an honest life until now.
可是一直以来 她都认真地活着
But she lost everything
却因为你失去了一切
without knowing what a despicable man you are.
甚至都不知道你的所作所为
There is nothing left in Ms. Yoshikawa's account,
吉川小姐的户口已经没什么钱了
and she is in debt.
而且已经欠债了
She will lose her job too.
她现在还会丢掉工作
Why are you blaming me for all of that?
这些怎么会怪到我头上来？
I don't understand.
莫名其妙
You may not have asked her to give you money or commit embezzlement.
或许你没有说过 要她给你钱或为你盗用公款
However, you drove her to do so.
但你有暗示她这么做 对吧？
Hey, we love each other.
喂 我跟她是两情相悦
She gave me money of her own will.
她甘愿为我奉献
What's wrong with that? Is that a crime?
这有问题吗？犯罪了吗？
She spent money to buy love. Isn't that fair?
她用钱买来爱情 很公道啊
With all due respect…
请恕我直言
she doesn't think she bought love with money.
她并不是打算用钱来买爱情
She…
吉川小姐
Ms. Yoshikawa just fell in love with you.
她只不过是喜欢你而已
She dreamed of a future with you,
她想跟你组织未来
and wanted to help you
想助你一臂之力
so she kept pushing herself,
所以一直勉勉强着自己
although it was in the wrong way.
只是她的做法是错的
But you are different.
而你却不一样
You deceived Ms. Yoshikawa.
你骗了吉川小姐 对吧？
So annoying.
烦死了
You pretended to love her in order to get money.
你只不过是为了钱 欺骗她的感情
Shut up!
住嘴
No, I won't.
我不要！
Hey.
喂
Did she say that she was deceived? I don't think so.
她并没有说过自己被骗了吧？
Because I didn't do that.
因为我根本没骗她
President Baba.
马场社长
It's not just Ms. Yoshikawa, right?
其实 不止吉川小姐吧？
What?
什么？
Ms. Keiko Okada.
冈田圭子小姐
Ms. Manami Hattori.
服部真奈美小姐
Ms. Aya Uno.
宇野亚耶小姐
You seem to be receiving money from many women.
你从这么多女性手中拿过钱呢
They're all saying that they're planning to marry you.
她们都说打算跟你结婚
Isn't this called fraud?
这是诈骗吧？
You will be investigated by the police for this as well.
关于这件事 你需要到警局接受审讯
I don't know how you will be judged by law.
我不知道法律会怎么制裁你
But…
但是
I will not forgive you.
我绝对不会原谅你
Never!
绝对不会！
We are from Azabu East Police.
我们是麻布东署的警察
We have been waiting for you.
你们终于来了
Are you Mr. Kouichi Baba?
你是马场浩一先生吧？
Please come with us.
麻烦你跟我们走一趟
Don't touch me.
别碰我
Senior Executive Director!
堂岛专务
Please give us a comment.
请发表一下意见
I am very sorry for the trouble and worry we have caused
这次在本行发生的现金失窃事件
regarding the stolen cash incident at our bank.
让各位担忧受惊 我深感歉意
The police and related authorities are investigating this case.
警方和有关部们正在调查这起案件
So I will decline to comment on the matter…
我不便多说…
You did a great job.
这次是你们两位的功劳啊
Was it a great job?
算得上功劳吗？
You prevented further crime and helped them catch the criminal.
你们避免了进一步的犯罪 协助警方捉拿罪犯
It was a great job.
当然算功劳啊
What's wrong with Ms. Hanasaki?
花琦她怎么了？
She's dealing with a lot of emotions right now.
她现在心情很复杂啦
I see.
好吧
I guess Ms. Hanasaki has a sensitive side to her too.
原来花琦也有脆弱的一面呢
Yes.
是啊
Surprisingly.
真没想到
THE MAIN SUSPECT WAS A MARRIAGE CON ARTIST
（主犯是结婚诈骗人）
FORMER EMPLOYEE AT TOKYO DAIICHI BANK SUSPECT KYOKO YOSHIKAWA
（东京第一银行前任职员 嫌疑人吉川恭子）
Hello, Senior Executive Director Doujima.
你好啊 堂岛专务
-Hello. -I'm sorry for your misfortune.
-你好 -这次真是飞来横祸啊
A scandal at the branch, managed by someone you are favoring.
是堂岛专务 你关照的分行经理管辖下的丑闻
It was a tough inaugural gift.
真是令人难受的就职礼物啊
I understand.
我理解你的心情
But it was not a big deal.
不过这也没什么大不了的
Something like that can't even be called a scandal.
那点程度的事情还算不上丑闻
But you shouldn't let your guard down.
可是 你还是别太大意
You never know what will cause you to unexpectedly fall at a bank.
毕竟在银行这种地方 自己怎么摔下来的都不知道啊
You are right.
你说得对
I will keep that in mind.
我会记住的
Thank you.
你客气了
Good work.
辛苦了
Excuse me.
我先告辞了
EXECUTIVE DIRECTOR'S OFFICE
（常务执行董事办公室）
What is it? You're sighing again?
怎么又叹气了？
Stop it. People will think that my dishes aren't tasty.
够了啦 免得顾客以为我的料理很难吃
Sorry.
对不起
What's wrong?
怎么了？
You're so docile today.
你今天特别听话啊
Dad.
爸
I don't know what it is to love someone.
喜欢一个人是怎么回事呢？
Huh?
什么？
Mai?
小舞
Are you in love?
你喜欢上谁了吗？
That's why you asked me such a serious question the other day.
所以你之前 才会问我那种深奥的问题啊？
No, I was just--
不是啦 我…
Is it Mr. Matsuki of Gotanda Branch?
是五反田分行的松木先生吗？
I'm Matsuki.
我是松木
Ms. Hanasaki, I can tell you really like it.
花琦小姐 看得出来你真的很喜欢啊
What?
什么啦？
I fully support that.
我举双手赞成哦
Dad, listen…
爸 你听我…
Good evening.
下午好
-Welcome. Listen, Mr. Soma. -Yes?
-欢迎光临 相马 你听我说 -是
What is it?
怎么了？
Mai is in love.
小舞恋爱了
-Love? -No.
-恋爱？ -不是啦
-Who is it? -Guess who?
-跟谁啊？ -那个嘛…
-No! Stop it. -Okay.
-好啦 够了 -好
I won't tell.
我不说
Do you want to know?
你想知道吗？
-Sure. -No.
-当然了 -不要
Stalker?
-跟踪狂？
It's someone in the Loan Department.
我怀疑是融资课的某个人
Shut up.
住嘴！
Let's investigate.
我们暗中监视吧
This case is closed.
这件事到此为止
I won't go easy on you.
我可不会因为你是女人就惯着你
It's a completely different case.
这是完全不一样的案件啊
You're the one who has to take
最需要负起责任的人
the responsibility.
是你